意大利 乌尔比诺 公爵宫
Ducal Palace Urbino, Italy.
大使先生
signore ambassador.
这真是失礼 贝多里先生
It's really most humiliating signore bedoli.
阁下 我道歉 阁下 请您见谅
My lord, prego, excellency, prego.
有什么事情如此重要
What could possibly be so important.
以至于我在早上7点前就得起床？
that you dragged me from my bed before 7 o'clock in the morning?
公爵召集了一次晨会 他要您出席
The duke has called an early meeting of the council he wanted you to attend.
就是今早
le matin.
先生
Monsieur.
为什么法国人在这里？
Why are the french here?
那就是殿下要和您商量的事儿
That is what his grace wants to talk to you about.
公爵大人
Excellence.
该死的法国佬
French bastards!
伦敦 白厅宫
Whiteball Palace London.
佩斯先生
Mr.Pace.
摩尔先生
Mr.More.
国王陛下要议会今天下午做简报
His majesty wants council this afternoon to be brief.
他不想听到长篇大论
He doesn't want a lot of speeches.
国王在哪儿？
Where is the king?
他正行私事 不可打扰
He's in seclusion and not to be disturbed.
他怎么样了？
How is he?
您指的是…
With regards to…?
我指的当然是意大利那边
With regard to italy!
法国佬在意大利所做的勾当
What the french are doing in italy.
那里还能有什么？
What other regard is there?
国王殿下还在耐心的商讨此事
His majesty is counselling patience.
但你是他的秘书
Yes, but you're his secretary.
你每天都见到他
You see him everyday.
在私下 他非常悲伤不已
In private he's mad with grief.
几近心碎
Almost inconsolable.
我想你应当记住被谋杀的是他的叔叔
I think you ought to remember it was his uncle they murdered.
国王陛下驾到
The king!
大臣们
My lords.
在此紧要关头 我们需聚此商议
We meet to consider questions of great moment.
法国国王已向世人展示了他侵略性的政策
The king of france has demonstrated to the world his aggressive policies.
他已侵入了5或6个意大利城邦
He has already overrun 5 or 6 city states in italy.
对欧洲每个基督教国家来说 他都是个威胁
He's a threat to every christian nation in europe,
他却又威胁教皇封他为信仰的卫冕者
yet he bullies the pope into declaring him defender of the faith.
除此之外 为了证明他无人能及的地位
On top of that, to prove that nobody can touch him.
他在乌尔比诺把我们的大使…
he has our ambassador in urbino…
也就是我的叔叔…
and my uncle…
谋杀了
murdered.
如此无情
In cold blood.
大臣们…
My lords…
我相信 这一切都是宣战的正当理由
I believe these are all just causes for war!
陛下明言
Your majesty is certainly right.
您有充分的理由来发动战争
You have every reason to prosecute a war.
说实在的 我在一年前 就提醒过您法国人的野心
Indeed, I warned you a year ago about french ambitions,
这次家门不幸才让陛下您相信我的话
though has taken this personal tragedy for your majesty to accept my word.
诺福克公爵
Norfolk.
我同意白金汉阁下
I agree with my lord buckingham.
英格兰之王历来便有权继承法国王位
The king of england has an ancient and historic right to the french throne,
却被瓦卢瓦家族篡夺
which the valois have usurped.
是时候把他们赶下台
It is high time we kick them out.
我们应当全力进攻法国
We should attack france with all our might.
正是
Yes.
你怎么想的 沃尔西？
What say you, wolsey?
我同意国王陛下您的话
I concur with your majesty.
这些的确是… 正当理由
These are indeed, just causes.
很好
Good!
那么决定了
Then it is settled.
我们将对法国开战
We are to war with france.
好啊
Yes!
主教阁下将做详细安排
Your eminence will make all the arrangements.
现在
Now!
我可以去玩了
I can go play.
你真觉得我们该开战？
Do you really think we should go to war?
我觉得我们应当按国王的心意行事
I think we should try to do what the king wants us to do.
如果国王不明白怎样才是最佳措施呢？
What if the king doesn't know what's in his best interests?
那样的话 你应当帮他决定
Then, you should help him decide.
你的丈夫怎么样了？
How is your husband?
我的丈夫？
My husband?
嫉妒极了
He's extremely jealous.
他威胁说要散布谣言
He's threatening to make a scandal.
说要把我丢进女修道院
Says he'll put me in a nunnery.
噢
Oh!
那可真是浪费
That would be such a waste.
萨里郡 汉普顿王宫
Hampton Court Surrey.
法国大使阁下与波尼维主教来访
His excellency the french ambassador and bishop bonnivet.
先生们 欢迎
Gentlemen, welcome.
阁下…
Your excellency…
我国大使在乌尔比诺被残杀 实为不幸
what happened in urbino, the butchering of our ambassador was most unfortunate.
尤其对我来说
Especially for me.
阁下应当知晓我对贵国的感情
Your excellency is well aware of my sentiments towards your country.
我为法国的利益不遗余力的奔走
I have laboured long ad consistently in french interests.
但这该如何解释？
But how to explain this?
谋杀我们国王的叔叔
The matter of my king's uncle.
坦白说 这不是我们国王的命令
Frankly, it was not done on my master's orders.
而犯下罪行的人业已处罚
And those that committed the crime have been punished.
现在 你得明白 我国并不将此事看得如此简单
Now, now, you must understand, we are well beyond that.
亨利陛下血气方刚
King henry is a young man.
他向来好战 而且这次 他不会就此罢休
He has an appetite for war and on this occasion he will not be easy to appease.
既然如此 那我们就开战吧
Then, by all means let us have war.
恕我直言 您应该言非此意
With the greatest respect, you don't mean that.
我相信我们应当竭尽全力
Well, I believe that everything humanly possible should be done.
来避免两国之战
to avoid a war between our 2 countries.
参与到「我们欧洲」的纠纷之中
It would do england no good.
对英格兰来说也是百害而无一利
to get involved in our european squabbles.
最好能置身乱世之外
Far better she stands above them.
我确信主教阁下有办法使年轻的狮子冷静下来
I'm sure your eminence has ways of pacifying the young lion.
得分
Play on!
15比0
15-love.
30比0
30-love.
打得好
Good shot.
我们赢定了 安东尼
Our game, I think, anthony.
陛下您知道我们是让着您赢的
Your majesty knows we're just lettin' you win.
其实我在拼命打
Actually, I was playing as hard as I can.
那里有个人 我得去碰碰运气
Now there is someone I have to try.
看见了吗 中间走廊 蓝色裙子 面容精致纯洁
See, middle gallery, blue dress, that exquisite virginal face.
她是谁？
Who is she?
40比0 终场
40-love.Game.
他是白金汉的女儿
She's buckingham's daughter.
100克朗 你搞不定
A hundred crowns, you don't succeed.
说定了
Done.
我们的女儿怎么样了？
How is our daughter?
她很好
She's well.
她的老师说她天资颖慧
You know her tutors say she has exceptional talents.
尤其是在音乐上
Especially in music.
你应当感到自豪
You should be proud.
我很自豪
I am.
你知道的 凯瑟琳
You know I am, katherine.
玛丽是我的掌上明珠
Mary is the pearl of my world.
你还没有给我的侄子回信
You have not answered my nephew's letters.
就因为你的侄子是西班牙国王
Just because your nephew's the king of spain.
他觉得我除了给他写信 就没有其他重要的事情了吗
Does he think I have nothing better to do?
你知道他建议你和罗马帝国签订协议
You know he advises you to sign a treaty with the emperor,
将法国列为我们的共同敌人
recognizing france as our mutual enemy.
他还建议你不要把沃尔西的话全都放在心上
He also advises you not to heed everything wolsey tells you.
因为沃尔西对法国很偏爱
because wolsey is so biased with the french.
你什么时候成外交家了？
Since when are you a diplomat?
有其父必有其女
I am my father's daughter.
你是我的妻子
You are my wife.
不是我的部长
You are not my minister.
不是我的总理
You are not my chancellor.
而是我的妻子
But my wife.
那就让我在各个方面都尽 为人妻的责任
I should like to be your wife in every way.
亨利 你还会不会像往常那样来我的卧房？
Henry, will you not visit my bed chamber as you used to?
吃吧
Eat.
睡袍
Gown.
陛下
Your majesty.
凯瑟琳皇后在哪里？
Where is the queen katherine?
皇后陛下还在做祷告 陛下
Her majesty is still at prayer, your majesty.
告诉皇后陛下…
Tell her majesty…
身为她的丈夫 我来此献上 我对她的真情和职责
I came to offer my love and devotion as her true husband.
遵命 陛下
yes, your majesty.
天主圣母玛利亚 为我等罪人 今祈天主 及我等死候
Holy mary, mother of god, pray for us now and at the hour of our death.
阿门
Amen.
万福玛利亚 满被圣宠者 主与尔偕焉
Hail mary, mother of grace, our lord is with thee blessed art.
女中尔为赞美 尔胎子耶稣并为赞美
thou amongst women and blessed is the fruit of thy womb.
简
Jane.
陛下…
Your majesty…
你愿意吗？
do you consent?
愿意 陛下
Yes, your majesty.
三分
3 points!
波特兰伯爵
Earl of portland!
查尔斯·布兰登阁下出场
Mr.Charles brandon has now entered the list.
陛下
Your majesties.
白金汉小姐 你可愿让我今日承蒙你的恩惠？
My lady buckingham, would you do me the honour of letting me wear your favours today?
哈勒姆爵士挑战
Lord hallam challenges.
请带上头盔
A plaisance!
倒地
A terre!
两分
Two points.
查尔斯-布兰登阁下
Mr.Charles brandon.
白金汉公爵陛下
His grace the duke of buckingham will now.
此刻将与纽卡斯尔伯爵进行马上长矛比斗
joust a plaisance with the earl of newcastle.
倒地
A terre!
公爵陛下又得三分
Another 3 points for his grace.
主教阁下可有计划？
Does your eminence have a plan?
来避免战争？
A way to avoid war?
这是新的和平协议的大纲
This is the outline of a new peace treaty.
联合英法
Uniting the english with the french.
我可否？
May I?
不
No.
我要你带走细细详读
I want you to take it away and read it very carefully.
我相信这代表着外交界里的一些新事物
I believe it represents something new in the world of diplomacy.
如贵王原则上同意 便可不失颜面的签署
If your king accepts it in principle he can sign it without any loss of face.
说实话 他可欣喜庆祝
Indeed, he can rejoice.
我的王可欣喜庆祝
My master can rejoice.
我们都可以欣喜庆祝
We can all rejoice.
主教阁下想要什么作为回报？
In which case, what does your eminence want in return?
什么都不要
Nothing.
什么都不要？
Nothing?
从你身上 什么都不要
Nothing from you.
我想要的… 阁下
What I want, your grace.
只有您能给我
Only you can give me.
白金汉公爵重新进入场
The duke of buckingham has re-entered the lists.
他已经赢了十回合
He's won 10 courses already.
他想证明什么？
What is he trying to prove?
让我来击败他
I'm gonna take him.
不 我来
No, I'll do it.
我想灭灭白金汉的威风
I'd love to damage buckingham's pride.
阁下 国王已经出场
My lords, the king has entered the list.
陛下来挑战？
His majesty makes the challenge?
开战
la guerre.
又来了
Here we go again.
不管认输与否
Claim or no claim.
白金汉都不是国王
Buckingham's not the king.
不是所有王公都像你那么忠诚 查尔斯
Not all of the court is as loyal as you charles.
我的夫人
My lady.
倒地
A terre!
陛下是今日胜者
His majesty wins the day.
国王陛下
The king.
减速
And easy!
立桨
Present oars!
托马斯
Thomas.
陛下
Your majesty.
这是我的家人
This is my family.
陛下
Your majesty.
我的妻子 爱丽丝
My wife alice.
爱丽丝 为国王殿下献吻
Alice, won't you kiss the king?
爱丽丝女士
Mistress alice.
陛下
Your majesty.
我们沿河散布 托马斯
Shall we walk by the river, thomas?
我喜欢步行
I like walking.
你为什么不来宫里住？
Why won't you come and live at court?
你该知道才对 我不喜欢
You know perfectly well why. I don't like it.
我的法律事业与我的生活都在这里
My legal practice and my life are here.
宫殿是给更有野心的人准备的
The court is for more ambitious men.
你上个月在议会上没怎么说话
You didn't say much in council last month.
关于什么？
About what?
和法国开战
Going to war with france.
作为人道主义者 我痛恨战争
As a humanist I have an abhorrence of war.
战争只适为兽行 执行者从来都不是野兽
It's an activity fit only for beasts yet practiced by no kind of beast.
反而都是人类
so constantly as by man.
作为人道主义者 我与你同感
As a humanist I share your opinion.
作为国王 我难以赞同
As a king I am forced to disagree.
说得像个律师似的
Spoken like a lawyer.
你知道的 是你教我的
You should know.You taught me!
看起来教的不够好
Not well enough, it seems.
你说完了吗？
Are you finished?
完了
Yes!
亨利
Harry!
我得劝告你 与其不惜任何代价开战
I must urge you that instead of spending ruinous amounts of money going to war,
不如用这些钱为人民谋福利
you should spend it rather, on the welfare of your people.
托马斯 我向你发誓…
Thomas, I swear to you…
我要成为一名正直的统治者
I intend to be a just ruler.
但告诉我：为何亨利五世被世人铭记？
But tell me this: Why is henry v remembered?
因为他捐助大学和建救济所？
Because he endowed universities and built alm's houses for the destitute?
不
No.
他被铭记着是因为他赢了阿金库尔之战
He is remembered because he won the battle of agincourt.
三千英格兰长弓手对六万法军
3000 english bowmen against 60000 frencH.
法国的骑士精英在四小时之内被击溃
The flower of french chivalry destroyed in 4 hours.
那场胜利让他成名 托马斯
That victory made him famous, thomas.
让他永垂不朽
It made him immortal.
这里任何一样都不是属于他的
He has no right to any of this.
他父亲在战场上收缴了王冠
His father seized the crown on the battlefield.
要不是靠他母氏家族的一个混蛋 他跟皇族还无瓜葛
He had no real claim to it, only through a bastard on his mother's side.
阁下的家族历史更悠久
Your grace's family is more ancient.
我是爱德华二世的直系后裔
I'm a direct descendant of edward ii.
这是我的王冠 这是我的宫殿
This is my crown and this is my court.
不是他的王冠 不是他的宫殿
Not his crown or his court.
您这可是叛国罪 阁下
That's treason, your grace.
这是事实
It's the truth.
终有一天…
And one day…
我们会让其成真
we shall make it come true.
阁下
Your grace.
怎么回事？
What's this?
布兰登
Brandon!
看起来像什么就是什么
It's what it looks like.
阁下
Your grace.
你强暴了我的女儿
You violated my daughter.
不
No.
不 她求我的
No, she begged.
你夺走了她的清白
You've taken her honour.
我向你保证 阁下 有人已经捷足先登
I swear to your grace, someone else was there before me.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a whore.
是啊 那倒是真的 阁下
Yes, that is true, your grace.
我该为此杀了你
I should kill you for this.
滚出去
Get out.
主教大人 布朗特女士来访
Eminence, lady blount is here.
很好
Very well.
主教大人
Your eminence.
我能为你做点什么 布朗特女士？
What can I dofor you, lady blount?
我…
I am…
怀孕了 主教大人
with child, your eminence.
然后呢…
Yes…
是陛下的孩子
it is his majesty's child.
你确定？
You are certain?
是的
Yes.
你告诉国王了吗？
Have you told the king?
没有
No.
很好
Good.
我会在合适的时候告诉陛下
I will inform his majesty in due time.
同时你以生命发誓 不会对任何人说起来这事情
In the mean time you will say nothing to anybody on pain of death.
明白了吗？
Do you understand?
到你遮盖不住肚子的时候 你会被…
When you are no longer able to hide your condition, you will be…
安排到一个隐蔽的地方修养
removed to a private place for your lying-in.
在那里你可以生下你的小杂种
There you can give birth to your bastard.
谢谢您 主教大人
Thank you, your eminence.
您会为我病重的孩子祝福吗？
Will you bless my sick child?
主教大人 求您倾听我的苦诉…
Your eminence, please draw me an audience…
各位 请为大人让路
oh my lords and masters, make way for his lord's grace.
主教大人
Your eminence.
啊 佩斯先生
Ah, mr.Pace.
我相信你有在帮我谋福利
I trust you are keeping a good eye on my interests?
那是自然 主教大人
Of course, your eminence.
像老鹰一样
Like an eagle.
我不要老鹰 佩斯先生
I don't want an eagle, mr.Pace.
他们飞的太高
They can soar too high.
要像鸽子 什么都盯着
Be a pigeon, shit on everything!
遵命 主教阁下
Yes, eminence.
国王在哪里？
Where is the king?
外出狩猎
Out hunting.
好 这让他心情顺畅
Good. It keeps him in good humour.
回来之后禀报一声
Send word when he returns.
遵命 主教大人
Yes, eminence.
你是什么人？
Who are you?
你想干吗？
What is it you want?
我有一封介绍信 大人
I have letters of introduction sir.
这是坎特伯雷教堂的教长写的
But these are from the dean of canterbury cathedral!
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
你可以自己引荐
Why did you not present yourself?
托马斯·塔利斯（16世纪英国作曲家）
Thomas tallis.
是我 大人
Yes, sir.
这上面说 你能演奏风琴 还有长笛
And you can play, it says, the organ and the flute.
而且歌唱得也还算不错
and can sing more than moderately well.
还有其它的吗？
Anything else?
是的 大人
Yes, siR.
我略懂作曲
I compose a little.
是吗
Indeed.
那么…
Well…
教长能否赏识你的才华
if the dean commends your talents…
我们还是拭目以待的好 不是吗
we shall have to see, won't we?
托马斯
Thomas.
我相信陛下今天狩猎很愉快
I trust your majesty enjoyed hunting today.
准备得怎么样了？
How are the preparations going?
非常不错
Very well.
您的军队和舰队正在集结
Both your army and fleet are assembling.
食物和武器供给正在准备中
Stores and provisions are being laid in.
几周之内您就可以宣战了
You could go to war in a matter of weeks.
很好
Excellent.
我知道这些琐事可以托付于你
I knew I could depend on you.
不胜感激 殿下
I am grateful to your majesty.
怎么了
What is it?
陛下 战争会耗费大量财力
Your majesty, wars are expensive.
您不得不提高税收来支付开销
To pay for them you have to raise taxes.
不得民心
That is not always popular.
陛下可以采取其他手段 来赢得权利和声望
What if your majesty could gain more power and prestige by other means?
其他手段？
Other means?
和平手段
Peaceful means.
什么
What!
没有战争？
No battles?
没有荣耀？
No glory?
我觉得陛下应该听他说完
I think your majesty should hear him out.
在过去的几周内 我代表陛下
In the past few weeks, I have conducted, on your majesty's behalf,
开展了一轮深入而激烈的外交磋商
an intense round of diplomatic talks.
不仅和法国大使 还有帝国皇帝的代表
Not just with the french ambassador but also with representatives of the emperor,
丹麦 葡萄牙 意大利联邦的特使…
with envoys from denmark, portugal, the italian states…
什么目的？
what for?
制定一项条约
To make a treaty.
什么样的条约？
What kind of treaty?
万邦永久和平条约
A treaty of universal and perpetual peace.
怎样实现？
How is it to be effected?
分几个阶段
In several stages.
首先 会举行一个会晤
In the first place there would be a summit meeting.
法国国王和英格兰国王之间
between the kings of france and england.
首脑会议议程之一 陛下的女儿 将会被正式许配给法国皇太子
At the summit, your majesty's daughter would be betrothed fory to the french dauphin.
会议结束的时候 您们都会签署条约
And at the end of the summit, you would both sign the treaty.
这项条约在欧洲历史上前所未有
The treaty is entirely new in the history of europe,
确保全体签约国
committing all its signatories.
之间的安全与和平
to the principles of collective security and universal peace.
怎样执行？
How would it be enforced?
如果任何签约国受到侵略
Should any of the signatory countries suffer aggression,
其他签约国将会立即要求侵略者撤退
all the others would immediately demand that the aggressor withdraws.
如果他们拒绝 其他签约国将会在一个月内对其宣战…
If he refuses, within 1 month the rest would declare against him…
直到恢复和平
and continue until peace is restored.
条约也勾画了一个泛欧共和体
The treaty also envisages the creation of pan-european institutions.
在某种程度上 我喜欢它
In some ways I like it.
我认同它…
I recognize it…
你也认同 托马斯
so do you, thomas.
是的
Indeed.
将人道主义法则应用于国际事务中
It's the application of humanist principles to international affairs.
恭喜主教大人
Your eminence is to be congratulated.
我不是来寻求赞赏的
I don't seek praise.
陛下将会被铭记为 一个崭新的现代世界的蓝图设计师
Your majesty would be known as the architect of a new and modern world.
那样我已心满意足
That would be reward enough.
你我永远肝胆相照
Always, be assured of our love.
先生们 晚安
Goodnight gentlemen.
什么事？
What is it?
陛下 白金汉公爵坚持求见
Your majesty, the duke of buckingham insists upon an audience.
公爵大人
Your grace.
陛下应该已经耳闻 我逮到查尔斯-布兰登
Your majesty ought to be made aware that I have discovered mr.Charles brandon.
轻薄我的女儿
in flagrante delicto with my daughter.
布兰登阁下使我的家族蒙羞
Mr.Brandon has brought shame to my family.
我要求陛下将他驱逐出宫廷
I demand that your majesty banish him from court.
并且处以其它陛下觉得合适的处罚
with whatever other punishment your majesty sees fit.
不会有处罚
There will be no punishment!
除非您女儿控告布兰登先生强奸
Unless your daughter accuses mr.Brandon of rape.
她有此控诉吗
Does she so claim?
您女儿控告布兰登先生强奸她吗？
Does your daughter claim mr.Brandon raped her?!
她不需要
She doesn't need to.
这是对我个人和我的家族的冒犯
The offence is against me and against my family!
据我所知 没有什么冒犯
As far as I know, there has been no offence.
所以也没必要处罚
So there is no need for any punishment.
陛下
Your majesty.
公爵大人
Your grace.
小心白金汉公爵 亨利
Be careful of buckingham, harry.
他可能很傻 但他比你富有
He may well be stupid, but he's richer than you are.
他有能力召集起一支私人军队
, and he can call upon a private army.
您父亲都没有顶撞过他
Not even your father crossed him.
我非常高兴法国国王同意签署条约
I'm very happy that the king of france has agreed to sign the treaty.
并且愿意主办首脑会议
and to host the summit.
陛下非常高兴能够避免开战
His majesty is delighted there will be no war.
我们大家都是
As we all are.
我们之前讨论的另外一件事呢？
What about the other matter we discussed?
哪一件 主教大人？
Which other matter, your eminence?
我帮过你家主子大忙
I saved your master's arse.
现在我想要回报
Now I want my reward.
你能够安排
And you can arrange it.
听明白了吗？
Do you understand?
小可怜
Poor you.
我们在被粗鲁地打断之前进行到哪了？
Now, where were we when we were so rudely interrupted?
查尔斯…
Charles…
我们不该这样做
we shouldn'T.
我父亲会杀了你
My father will kill you.
那我也将含笑上路
Then I shall die a happy man.
好了…
Now…
你们都读完了吗？
have you all finished your reading?
是的 父亲
Yes, father.
是的
Yes.
非常好
Very well.
愿上帝和天使保佑你们 今晚与你们作伴 直到永久
May god and his angels bless you and keep you this night and always.
晚安
Goodnight.
晚安 孩子们
Goodnight children.
住手
Stop.
陛下 给弗朗西斯国王的信 该如何下笔
The letter to king francis, your majesty.
我亲爱的高贵的表弟…
My dearest royal cousin…
不
no.
改成我心爱的表弟
Make that my beloved cousin.
致以我们的爱意
We send you our love.
我们爱你之深 无从更深
We love you so much it would be impossible to love you better.
把一切安排妥当 好让我们能当面谈谈
Make all the necessary arrangements so we may meet face to face.
现在没有其它比这万邦和平条约 更贴近我心 更珍贵
Nothing is now closer or more dear to my heart than this treaty of universal peace.
作为我美好的意愿 以及对此条约的承诺
As a token of my good will, my commitment to this treaty,
还有我对陛下的爱意
and my love for your majesty,
我决定…
I have decided…
是的 陛下
yes, majesty.
我决定在我们见面之前不会再剃胡须
I have decided I will not shave again until we meet.
我的胡须将成为我们之间友谊 爱意
My beard will be a token of universal friendship,
的象征
of the love between us.
主教大人
Your eminence.
公爵大人
Your grace.
我有些消息给您
I have some news for your eminence.
亚历山大教皇陛下 已经病入膏肓了
His holiness, pope alexander, is desperately ill.
离归西不久已
It cannot be long before he is summoned to god's house.
考虑到主教大人众所周知的虔诚
In view of your eminence's well-known piety,
以及您渊博的学识和高超的外交手段
as well as your great learning and diplomatic skills.
我保证主教大人在选举教宗的 枢机主教团秘密会议上
I can assure your eminence of the support of the french cardinals.
会得到法国红衣主教们的支持
at the conclave to elect a successor.
再加上您属下红衣主教们的选票
With the votes of your own cardinals.
如果上帝也许可 您将成为新任教宗
and if it is pleasing to god you will be elected pope,
罗马主教 我们的新任圣父
bishop of rome our new holy father.
谢谢 主教大人
Thank you, your grace.
您让我觉得…
You make me feel…
非常卑微
truly humble.
您病了吗 布朗特女士？
Are you ill, lady blount?
不 陛下
No, your majesty.
请留一下
Please, stay.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Goodnight.
我很久没和人谈过心了
I have not talked to anyone for a long time.
红衣主教沃尔西 遣散了我的西班牙神父
Cardinal wolsey dismissed my spanish confessor.
和大部分西班牙侍女 以防他们是间谍
and most of my spanish ladies in case they were spies.
我又无法信任英国神父
And I cannot trust my english confessor.
但我能信任你 我可以信任你吗 布朗特夫人？
But I can trust you though, can I not, lady blount?
是 夫人
Yes, madam.
我悲从何来？
What is my sadness?
是因为…
It is that I…
我无法给国王一个活着的子嗣
I cannot give the king a living son.
我曾生过一个小男孩
I gave birth to a baby boy once.
可爱的男孩…
A sweet boy…
但他死了…
but he died…
死在我怀里…
in my arms…
活了仅仅4周
after just 4 weeks of life.
国王怪罪我
The king blames me.
我知道
I know.
他认定都是我的错
He thinks it all my fault!
他不知道我受了多大折磨 做了多少祈祷
He does not know how much I suffer, how much I pray.
我一直想起兄长
I've been thinking about my brother.
亚瑟
Arthur.
他死去时 我被注定要娶凯瑟琳为妻
When he died it was decided that I should marry katherine.
我想是父亲不愿失去她继承的财产
I think my father didn't want to lose her dowry.
或是跟西班牙联姻…
Or the prestige…
带来的威望
of a spanish marriage.
无论如何…
In any case…
凯瑟琳发誓她跟兄长不曾圆房
katherine swore the marriage was never consummated.
因此教皇准许了婚姻解除
That's why a papal dispensation was granted.
因此我娶了她
And so I married her.
从那时开始 我们有过5个夭折的孩子
And since then we have had 5 still-born children.
一个男孩…
A boy…
只活了26天…
who lived for 26 days…
和唯独活下来的一个女儿
And a single living daughter.
如果他们已经圆房了呢？
What if their marriage was consummated?
她对上帝发誓过没有
She has sworn before god that it was not.
福音书里怎么说来着？
What does it say in the gospels?
若男子娶其兄嫂？
If a man should marry his brother's wife?
告诉我
Tell me.
「利未记」中说…
In leviticus…
「若男子娶其兄嫂
it says: "If a man marries his brother's wife,
二人至死不得后代「
they will die childless".
可你有孩子
But you have a child.
但不是儿子
But not a son!
我没有儿子
I have no son.
托马斯·博林到访 大人
Thomas boleyn, your grace.
托马斯伯爵
Sir thomas.
希望您没有觉得我的邀请过于冒失
I hope you didn't find my invitation presumptuous.
听说您从法国被召回了
I heard you had been recalled from france.
我停留不久 大人
I'm here for a short while, your grace.
请
Come.
他们告诉我您是出色的大使
They tell me you are an excellent ambassador.
不管他们是谁 他们真友善
Then, whoever they are, they are very kind.
您来自古老的家族
You come from an old family.
论古老和庞大 远不及大人您的氏族
Though not as ancient, nor as grand, as your grace'S.
国王选择平民围绕他左右 无地位 无声望
The king chooses to surround himself with commoners,
无血统 无头衔的下三九流
men of no distinction, new men, without pedigree or titles.
这对他王权有何帮助？
How does that help the prestige of his crown?
- 大人 我… - 他父亲用武力而非权利夺得了王位
- Your grace, I - his father only acquired the crown by force not by right!
大人 没人愿意重返内战的暗无天日
Your grace, no one wants to return to the evil days of civil war.
既成事实 回天乏力
What is done is done.
国王即国王
The king is the king.
沃尔西
Wolsey.
那个有情人还有两个孩子的教士
A man of the cloth with a mistress and two children.
你会中意这个人吗？
How do you like this fellow?
决不
Not at all.
我们下次再聊
We shall talk again.
给我讲讲法国国王 托马斯伯爵
Tell me about king francis, sir thomas.
他23岁
He is 23 years old.
高吗？
Is he tall?
高
Yes.
但长得不匀称
But ill-proportioned.
腿呢？
What about his legs?
他的小腿强壮吗 跟我的一样？
Are his calves strong, like mine?
陛下 没人的小腿能比得上您的
Majesty, no one has calves like yours.
他英俊吗？
Is he handsome?
会有些人这么觉得吧
Some people might think so.
他自己当然是这么觉得
He certainly thinks so himself.
他那么虚荣吗？
He's vain?
陛下 他是法国人啊
Your majesty, he's french!
他的宫廷如何？
What about his court?
她以道德松散 放荡淫乱闻名
It has a reputation for loose morals and licentiousness,
而就国王自己而言 这没什么好整顿的
which the king, by his own behaviour, does nothing to dispel.
你有两个女儿 托马斯爵士
You have two daughters, sir thomas.
你怎么保护她们？
How do you protect them?
我一直警惕着她们身边
I keep a watchful eye on them.
但同时信任她们自有贞洁操守
But I also trust in their goodness and virtue.
请你立即启程回巴黎
You will return immediately to paris.
我委托你代理一切首脑会议的外交谈判
I am entrusting you with all the diplomatic negotiations for the summit.
将
Checkmate.
玛丽…
Your majesty…
玛丽
mary!
爸爸
Papa.
谁敢说你不美丽？
Aren't you beautiful?
你难道不是世上最美丽的女孩？
Aren't you the most beautiful girl in the world?
我不知道呀
I don't know.
你当然是
Yes you are.
感觉怎么样？
How do you feel?
好
Well.
好？
Well?
爸爸很忙
Papa's busy.
要乖
Be good.
听大人的话
Do everything you are told.
可以说句话吗？
May we speak?
你们继续
Continue.
我的夫人
My lady.
陛下
Majesty.
我不喜欢
I do not like it.
不喜欢什么？
What don't you like?
你的胡子
Your beard.
更不喜欢它的含义
Nor what it represents.
凯瑟琳
Katherine.
你要把我女儿 送给法国和他们王太子
You are giving my daughter away to the dauphin and to france.
甚至没有征求过我的意见
You did not even consult me.
瓦卢瓦王朝是我氏族的死敌
The valois are the sworn enemies of my family.
我要按我认为恰当的方式安排她
She is mine to do with as I see fit.
这是一场伟大的联姻
It's a great marriage.
我知道沃尔西就是幕后黑手
I see wolsey's hand behind this.
纵使我深爱陛下
Though I love your majesty,
对你忠贞不苟
and am loyal to you in every way,
也不能掩饰我的忧伤与不快
I cannot disguise my distress and unhappiness.
做不到也要做
Well you're going to have to.
法国 巴黎
Paris, France.
早安 大使先生
Bonjour monsieur l'ambassadeur.
有您一封要函
Il y a des messages pour vous.
国王明天接见您
Et demain vous avez une audience avec le roi.
很好
Trbien.
谢谢你 皮埃尔
Merci pierre.
我的女儿们在哪里？
Where are my daughters?
我有令人兴奋的好消息
I have some exciting news.
弗朗西斯国王和亨利国王 将在加来市附近会见
There is to be a summit between king francis and king henry near calais.
我负责准备安排
I am to arrange it.
意味着你们姐妹俩 都有机会见到英国国王
That means you will both have the opportunity to meet the king of england!
玛利
Mary.
还有我的安妮 博林
And anne.Boleyn.
敬你们的将来
To your futures!
沃尔西红衣主教到
His eminence cardinal wolsey.
我需要你的意见
I want your opinion.
觉得这件衣裳如何？
Do you like this cloth?
非常适合陛下您
I think it suits your majesty very well.
请允许我建议 或许…
Perhaps, if I might suggest…
应该配上这些
with these.
你觉得弗朗西斯有这么精美的饰物吗？
Do you think francis will have anything as fine as these?
有也是他偷来的
Only if he steals them.
跟我来
Come.
我们共餐
Let's eat together.
畅谈一番
We can talk.
等等
Hold.
大人 你要道歉
Your grace will apologize.
我说…
I said…!
你要道歉
You will apologize.
如果触犯了陛下您 我道歉
I apologize if I have offended your majesty.
大人你可以离开了
Your grace may leave us.
侍者 给大法官拿双新鞋
Boy, fetch the chancellor a new pair of shoes!
霍普金斯
Hopkins!
大人
Your grace.
是时候了
It's time.
跟我说说
Speak to me.
是 那么…
Yes, well…
首脑会议一切准备就绪
everything is prepared for the summit.
地点在加来市范围 属英国领土
It will take place in the pale of calais, english territory.
在名为Val D'or的山谷中 意为黄金山谷
In a valley known as the val d'or, the valley of gold.
千名工人为陛下您建造了一座宫殿
A thousand labourers have constructed a palace for your majesty.
被称为幻象之宫
It's known as the palace of illusions.
有人甚至称它为世界第8大奇迹
Some say it's the 8th wonder of the world!
你去买来所有能找到的金银
You are to purchase as much cloth of gold and silver as you can find.
贿赂卫兵用它们再好不过
It is a better thing to bribe the guards with.
遵命 大人
Yes, your grace.
然后 我要你到我们的领地去 照之前讨论决定的来做
Then I want you to proceed to our estates and do as we discussed,
制造些动乱 好让人以为 我们招兵买马是为了自卫
just making some noise that we're only raising men to defend ourselves.
遵命 大人
Yes, your grace.
布朗特夫人有了身孕
Lady blount is with child.
布朗特夫人？
Lady blount?
若您想留下这婴儿
If you want to keep the child,
我可以安排她住到耶利哥的别馆
I will arrange for her to be moved to the house at jericho.
也会处理好她丈夫相关事宜
I will also deal with her husband.
我父亲…
my father…
曾告诉我 他计划如何刺杀理查三世
once told me how he had planned to assassinate richard iii.
他把刀藏在衣服里 走到他面前
He would come before him with a knife secreted about his person.
陛下
Your majesty!
我都等不及首脑会议的举行
I can't wait for this summit!
它将永远改变世界
It'll change the world forever.
这是我最由衷的希望 以及最坚定的信念
That is my dearest hope, and my ultimate belief.
翻天覆地的变化即将发生 阁下
Nothing will ever be the same, your eminence.
你我将不朽
You and I will be immortal.